Let's get started with the first step of the data analysis process: asking questions.
لنبدأ بالخطوة الأولى في عملية تحليل البيانات: طرح الأسئلة.
If you remember from the overview video,
إذا كنت تتذكر فيديو النظرة العامة،
sometimes we ask our questions
فإننا في بعض الأحيان نطرح الأسئلة
first and use them to direct what types of data we'll get later.
أولاً ونستخدمها لتوجيه أنواع البيانات التي سنحصل عليها لاحقًا.
Other times, we'll get our data first and ask questions based on it.
وفي أحيان أخرى، سنحصل على بياناتنا أولاً ونطرح الأسئلة بناءً عليها.
Here, we're going to practice creating questions with the real data set.
وفي هذا الدرس، سنقوم بطرح أسئلة باستخدام مجموعة البيانات الحقيقية.
This is data from the University of Wisconsin General Surgery Lab and the measurements of
هذه البيانات مأخوذة من مختبر الجراحة العامة بجامعة ويسكونسن وقياسات
tumors extracted during biopsies along with
الأورام المستخلصة خلال الخزعات مع
the designation of whether or not the tumor was cancerous.
تحديد ما إذا كان الورم سرطانًيا أم لا.
A natural question would be: how do we know if a tumor is cancerous?
السؤال الطبيعي هو: كيف نعرف إذا كان الورم سرطانيًا؟
This is a pretty broad question.
هذا سؤال واسع جدا.
It will be helpful to formulate intermediate questions to guide our analysis.
سيكون من المفيد صياغة أسئلة وسيطة لتوجيه تحليلنا.
Here is the Notebook I made,
هذا دفتر ملاحظات قمت بإعداده،
which you'll be working through later.
والذي ستعملون من خلاله لاحقًا.
Take a closer look at the features and think about questions that would help
يمكنك إلقاء نظرة فاحصة على الميزات والتفكير في الأسئلة التي ستساعدك
you learn more about these features and their relationships in the data.
في معرفة المزيد عن هذه الميزات وعلاقاتها في البيانات.
One example would be,
ومن الأمثلة على ذلك،
does the size of the tumor determine its malignancy?
هل يحدد حجم الورم كونه ورمًا خبيثًا؟
You'll find out more information about this data set in the instructor notes below.
ستجد المزيد من المعلومات حول مجموعة البيانات هذه في ملاحظات المعلم أدناه.
What additional questions you have about the data?
ما الأسئلة الإضافية التي لديك عن البيانات؟
How do you go about analyzing the data?
كيف ستقوم بتحليل البيانات؟